意志的薄弱使我们受制于死亡
We yield to death through weakness of will.
它将我们的灵魂放逐至无尽的虚无
It banishes our souls into the great emptiness.
无论那有多深邃
...and whatever lies beyond.
但要是某种人类的灵魂可以使用另一种力量
But what if one human spirit could draw upon the power of another...
以永恒为生又会怎么样？
...and live for all eternity?
黑色死神的疾病将要把我带走
有一天也你会被带走
这是我们所拥有的力量要付出的代价
你看起来很整洁
You look clean.
我想是神奇的肥皂泡和水的功劳
Miracle soap and water, I guess.
想要再变得脏点吗
Wanna get dirty again?
18世纪末19世纪初许多重要的作家和诗人
Many of the important writers and poets the late 18th and early 19th century...
比如拜伦 济慈 坡
...I name Byron, Keats, Poe,
他们对我的工作产生了极大的影响
as they have most influenced my work,
分享着对死亡主题的激情
shared a passion for the macabre.
他们还有其他的共同之处
They also had another thing in common:
他们的探索为寻找到
their quest to find...
最极致的美
...absolute beauty.
一种让人永恒愉悦
A thing of beauty...
的美丽事物
...is a joy forever.
这种美丽的力量
Its loveliness increases...
将永不会被虚无所吞噬
...it will never pass into nothingness.'
济慈同样也写到
Keats also wrote:
永生的鸟啊 你不为死亡而生
Thou is not born for death, immortal bird.
饥饿的时代无法把你蹂躏
No hungry generations tred thee down.'
出自济慈的《夜莺颂》
但我
But I...
不想将这主题发展成冗长的演讲 让我们去享用午餐吧
I won't tred this genration down with a longer lecture, let's go to lunch!
谢谢
Thank you.
Thanks.
就是这样
That's it.
很棒的工作  谢谢
Nice job. Thanks man.
我希望知道如何才能获得激发听众热情的能力
Wish I knew how to get that kind of enthusiasm out of 'em.
我能问你些事么  你看那个一身黑衣的女孩 她还在这里
Can I ask you something? Um- You see the girl, still in here, with all black on?
她怎么了
Mhm... What about her?
她至少来听过6次我的演讲 就在离这200英里远的地方
She's been to at least six of my lectures, long well over 200 miles away from here.
你认识她吗
Do you know her?
是的，她也是我们中的一员
Yeah, she's one of ours.
宗教比拟学的研究生
Grad student in comparative religion.
研究生
Grad student?
怎么 你以为她是大学生里的摇滚乐迷
What, did you think she was an undergrad groupie?
是啊
Yeah...
她叫什么
Well, what's her name?
丽姬娅 罗马诺娃
Ligeia Romanova.
丽姬娅 是个外国名字
'Ligeia?' That's exotic.
非常迷人
Yeah, quite fetching, huh?
你忘记我已经订婚了
You forgot that I'm engaged?
-人人都觉得这太可恨了          - 你这冷嘲热讽的老家伙
-Everybody should be so cursed. -You cynical old man!
明晚教职工聚会上再见
See you both at the faculty party tomorrow night?
该死 当然了
Hell yeah, of course.
-说好了     -再见
-All right. -See ya, Len.
女士 抱歉 抱歉 女士
Miss? Miss? Uh, excuse me. 'Scuse me, miss?
嗨 我最近经常看到你
Hey, I've been seeing a lot of you lately, huh?
你一直在跟着我
Are you following me?
是啊 我对你的书非常着迷
Well, your books fascinate me.
你那高雅的诗歌阅读仿佛是由一种独特的能量所组成
You seem to read poetry on a higher level, like it was a form of energy.
这 这 真是一个很有趣的评价
It is... It's an interesting assessment.
那么，你在学宗教比拟学                  - 现在谁才是暗恋者
So, uh, you study comparative religion? -Now who's the stalker?
不 额 是波利斯校长告诉我的
No, no, uh, chancellor Burris told me.
神秘主义 千真万确 这才是我真的爱好
Mysticism, really. That's my true passion.
真的
Really?
那么 明天晚上的教职工聚会上能见到你吗
So, am I going to see you at the faculty party tomorrow night?
你是在邀请我
Are you inviting me?
额 不 我 额
Uh, no, no, I'm, uh...
开始后悔自己的决定了
Regreting your discision already?
不 什么  不
No, what? No.
那么在这种情况下 我要穿得性感些
So in that case,I'm gonna wear... something sexy.
这是我的名片 梅里克教授
Take my card, Professor Merrick.
你会需要它的
You'll need it.
让我把您的盘子换走
-Lemme get that outta your way.
玩得愉快吗 乔治
Are you having a good time, George?
好坏参半
I have some mixed feelings.
听着，别管那些 你得到了我美丽的罗
Listen, put it this way, you get my beautiful Row, and...
我想要的就是一次酣畅淋漓的宿醉
...all I'm gonna have is a magnificent hangover.
喔 爸爸
Aww, dad...
乔纳森 我的孩子
Jonathan, my boy.
我道歉 谢谢你为婚礼掏的钱
I, um, apologize, and I thank you for paying for the wedding.
别担心 这没什么问题
Don't worry, that's no problem.
我生而就具有一笔财富
I was born with a silver spoon.
那好，即然你提到了
Well, as long as you brought it up...
你的财富 死亡的双亲 我的意思是
...your rich, dead parents, I mean...
-爸爸，住口 - 哦
-Dad, Stop! -Oh!?
我可以免除那些财富在你身上的负担
I can relieve you of some of the burden of you and your spoon.
等等，这一点不好玩
Wait, that's not funny!
至始至终
By the Alpha and Omega...
起始与结束
...beginning and end...
现身吧
Show yourself.
谢谢
Thank you very much.
啊哈
Ahem.
Ahem...
当然了
Of course.
爸爸，明晚教职工聚会之后我们带你去检查
-Dad, we'll come check on you after the faculty party tomorrow night.
好吗
Okay?
我不是孩子了，罗
I'm not a baby, Row.
发生什么了
What's happening?
他死了
Is he dead?
这公式  它需要更多的验证
The formula; It needs more work.
丽姬娅  我应该如何摆脱这些玩意
Ligeia, how am I supposed to get rid of it...
校长
Chancellor!?
我的博士研究课题       我不这么认为
My doctoral research. -I think not.
你在这里获得了什么
What do you have there?
证明   - 证明什么
Proof. -Of What?
证明灵魂
Proof that the spirit...
可以被控制
...can be contained...
可以被支配
...and controlled.
生存的证明
Proof of survival.
这都是些什么鬼东西
What the fuck?
罗马诺娃女士
Miss Romanova
我可不会被你这小把戏所骗
I'm not falling for your little hoax!
这可是个严肃的学术研究机构 不是巫术
This is an institution for serious studies. Not witchcraft.
我向你保证这是无比真实的
I assure you it's quite real.
你可以放弃从这个学校获得学位的幻想了
You can forget about getting a degree from this school.
我要撤销你的奖学金权利
...and I'm going to revoke your scholarship privileges.
校长
Chancellor...
这不是你在你妻子床上操我的时候所承诺的
That's not what you promised me when you were fucking me on your wife's bed.
现在，离开这。
Now, get out of here.
如果他撤销了你的奖学金，那这个实验就结束了
If he pulls your scholarship, this experiment is through.
我希望你知道你和梅里克教授之间在做什么
I hope you know what you are doing with Professor Merrick.
乔纳森
Jonathan...
聆听我 乔纳森
Hear me, Jonathan.
乔纳森
Jonathan...
Jonathan!
渴望我 乔纳森
Desire me, Jonathan...
乔纳森
Jonathan...
爱慕我 乔纳森
Worship me, Jonathan...
来我身边
Come to me.
我很高兴你的决定
I'm glad you decided to come.
如你所见，我同样喜欢死亡的主题
As you can see, I too, like the macabre.
喝下它
Drink this.
它尝上去就像乙醇和欧亚甘草
That tastes like grain alcohol and licorice.
苦艾酒
Absinthe.
这些东西会让人变得疯狂
The stuff that makes people go crazy?
有些人是这么说的
Some people say that.
如果我错了请你指正 梵高不是在饮用
Correct me if I'm wrong, but didn't Van Gogh
苦艾酒后极度兴奋之下割下了自己的耳朵
cut off his ear in an absinthe delirium?
但他已经疯了
But he was already certifiable.
（俄语）干杯
Na zdorovie.
现在我可以给你展示你生命中的倒影
Now I can show you life looking back at you.
看
Look.
我称呼它为我的“灵魂之镜”
I call it my 'Soul Mirror.'
这里
There...
你看到了吗
Do you see it?
这是什么鬼东西
What the hell?
基督啊
Jesus!
现在 让我们看看你的
Now, let's see yours.
你身上游荡着性的渴望
You're vibrating with so much sexual energy.
你并不确定自己属于她
You're not sure you belong with her.
你并不了解我
You don't know me.
是吗
Don't I?
我可以等着
I can wait.
梅里克教授
Professor Merrick.
嗨
-Hi!
恭喜你的新书出版 乔纳森
Congratulations on your new book, Jonathan.
谢谢，波利斯太太
-Thanks, Mrs. Burris.
嘿 莱恩
Hey, Len.
嘿 乔恩  我很高兴你能赶来
Hey Jon, I'm glad you could make it.
-这是我们的女歌手      - 一如既往的美丽
-Here's our songbird. -Beautiful as ever.
谢谢 很高兴见到你 莱恩
Thank you, nice to see you, Len.
谢谢 喔
Yeah, thanks... oh!
你还好吗
Are you okay?
赶紧离开酒吧
Let's get away from the bar.
也许是我喝得太多了
Should probably be mixing more than I'm drinking,
不过我觉得好些了
but I feel alright.
那么 罗威娜 乔纳森告诉我你已经准备好很快登上舞台的中心
So, Rowena, Jonathan tells me that you'll be ready for center stage real soon.
哦 上帝啊 不 他是夸大其词 不过谢谢你
Oh, God, no! He's exaggerating, but thank you!
事实上我也许会在欧洲和俄罗斯之间举办一个巡回音乐剧
I might actually be doing a musical that's touring Europe and Russia...
真的吗
Really?
是啊，我已经当了好久的预备演员了 我希望这次能让我成功
Yeah, I've been an understudy for so long, I'm hoping this works out.
俄罗斯人喜欢音乐剧
-They like musicals in Russia?
是的 我也许要在莫斯科呆几个月
-They do! I might just be in Moscow in a few months.
但是，再说吧
But, we'll see.
太好了 抱歉
-Oh, great. Excuse me.
-这是个私人聚会            -我在宾客名单上
-This is a private affair. -I'm on the guest list.
我出去抽两口烟
-I'm going out for a smoke.
-我以为你对他们放弃希望了  –我确实
-I thought you gave 'em up? -I did.
-嘿   -嗨
-Hey. -Hi.
你不介绍下我们吗
Aren't you going to introduce us?
恩，额，罗威纳 这是丽姬娅
Yeah, uhm, Rowena, this is Ligeia.
乔纳森跟我说了很多关于你的事
Jonathan's told me so much about you.
他真的做了
-He has, has he?
你想要喝一杯吗   想喝一杯吗
Do you want a drink? Would you like a drink?
我不确定你这有苦艾酒
-I don't suppose you have any absinthe?
没，我这有马提尼 这也行
No, we have martinis. -It'll do.
酒
Wine?
丽姬娅是个很有趣的名字
Ligeia is a very interesting name.
是俄罗斯名字
It is Russian.
哈 俄语是非常美妙的语言
Hmm! Russian is a beautiful language.
这有什么含义吗
What does that mean?
我绝不会说的
I'll never tell.
我们走吧
-Here we go.
- 很高兴见到你                 -哦 当然 同样很高兴见到你
-It was very nice to meet you. -Oh, yes. Likewise.
真的很好
Really nice.
啊哈
Ahem!
什么  - 什么
What? - What?
‘我在宾客名单上’ 这是怎么回事
'I'm on ze guest list.' What the hell was that?
不，这不是你想的那样
No, it's not what your thinking.
这听起来不怎么谦逊 不过
Not to sound modest, but...
我是个有前途的教授 如果有一个年轻单纯的
I'm a pretty good lecturer. I can't help it if some
女孩子对我产生某种奇怪的迷恋 我也没有办法
impressionable young woman develops a wierd crush.
当然不会
Of course not.
她可是难以置信的漂亮
'Cus she's incredibly beautiful.
额
Uh-oh...
你是在嫉妒啊
Are you jealous?
不
No...
是的
Yes.
你瞧，生命是如此容易消逝除非你为此而努力奋斗
You see, life falls away, unless you fight for it.
你并没有明白，不是吗
You really don't get it, do you?
你知道 当你第一次来到这所大学的时候
You know, when you first came to this university,
我对你的研究抱有极高的期望
I had such high hopes for your research.
明天 我会撤销你的大学项目资金
Tomorrow I'm cutting off your university funding.
诚实点说 我宁可你没有和她谈过话
Honestly, I would just rather you not talk to her.
永远没有
Like, ever!
好的
-Ok.
你觉得我是否小心眼
You don't think I'm being petty, do you?
不
No.
你确定没有其他改变你心意的方法了
You sure there's no way I can change your mind?
我不想做那些使你苦恼的事情
I don't want to do anything to worry you.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry that...
事情必须发展成这样
...this is the way it has to be.
我爱你
I love you.
莱恩
Len?
上帝啊 你的眼睛
Jesus, man! Your eyes!
不 不 不
No, no, no!
快来人
Somebody help!
-到了医院我再打给你             - 再见
-I'll call you from the hospital. -Bye.
抱歉 我想要一起搭个车
'Scuse me. I'd like to ride along.
-你是家属吗      -不是
-Are you family? -No.
好吧，那你得和我们在医院见面
Well, then your gonna have to meet us at the hospital.
他双眼在不停流血 你以前看到过这样的情况吗
-He was bleeding from the eyes. Have you ever seen that before?
我们会照看好他的
-We will take good care of him.
没事的 乔纳森 我们会在医院见面的
It's ok, Jonathan. We'll see you at the hospital.
需要搭个车吗
Need a ride?
她没必要知道
She doesn't have to know.
你知道 我知道 我们都感觉到了
You know, I know; We both feel it.
就好像有什么东西在你的内心灼烧
It's like something burning under your skin.
一时的化学反应造就的冲动说明不了什么
Chemistry doesn't mean acting on every impulse.
有时让步于自己的冲动
Sometimes giving in to an impulse...
就好比听从音乐的节拍那样自然
...is as simple as surrendering to music.
-早上好 亲爱的         -早上好
-Good morning, honey. -Good morning.
乔纳森还在医院吗
-Is Jonathan still at the hospital?
是的
-Yeah.
-你有睡过觉吗          - 有 怎么了
-Did you get any sleep? -Yeah, why?
有个白痴在午夜的时候打电话
Well, some fool called in the middle of the night.
是谁啊
Who was it?
我不知道，我没接
-I don't know, I didn't pick it up.
去把它转去了人工应答
I let it go to the machine.
一条信息
Message one;
罗威娜  我给你点关于你未婚夫的建议 他在和别的女人鬼混
Rowena, I'm advising you about your fianc? He is fucking another woman.
就在兰斯福德 700号公寓
At the Ransford. Apartment 700.
开门
Open the fucking door.
请进
Please, come in.
他在哪
Where is he?
我们刚刚沐浴过
We were just having a shower.
你想要加入我们吗
Would you like to join us?
上帝啊
God...
罗
Row.
丽姬娅 快点 我们走吧
Ligeia. Come on, let's go.
波利斯太太
Mrs. Burris?
你好 乔纳森
Hello, Jonathan.
对不起
I'm so sorry.
如果这里有什么我可以帮忙的
If there's anything I can do...
谢谢
Thank you.
有什么问题吗
-What's the problem?
-我的补偿         -我们已经在谈这个
-My compensation. -We already talked about it.
要是乔纳森发现是我打给他的未婚妻怎么办
What if Jonathan found out I called his fianc?
别威胁我，你这混蛋
Don't blackmail me, you little shit.
我会毁灭你
I will destroy you.
想我了没
Do you miss me?
亲爱的 亲爱的艾迪
My dear, sweet Eddie...
你在我心中一直占据着一块位置
I will always have a place for you in my heart.
那病变得更糟糕了
没有变得更好
It isn't getting better.
我很好
I'm fine.
我会好起来的
I'll be ok.
她死了  是什么让你觉得这会有什么不同
She's dead. What makes you think this will be any different?
这么多年来她一个月只离开过这公寓2次
She only left the apartment twice a month for years.
她的灵魂仍然在这
Her spirit will be close.
由始至终
By the Alpha and Omega...
起始与终结
...beginning and end...
现身吧
Show yourself.
这就是
There it is.
你不知道我花了多长时间致力于这公式的研究
You have no idea how long I worked on this formula.
我希望这一切都是值得的
I hope it's worth it.
哦 最终这会
Oh, it will be...
是值得的
...in the end.
我不知道发生了什么 莱恩
I don't know what going on, Len.
我只有点陷入对她的迷恋
I just sort of fell into her.
她将我身体中的黑暗释放出来
She's bringing out this darkness in me.
让我们来点苦艾酒
Let's have some absinthe.
你一定是乔纳森
You must be Jonathan.
是的
Yes.
她是独一无二的  我希望你能了解这一点
There is no-one else quite like her. I hope you know that.
-你没告诉你你病得这么重             -我很害怕
-You didn't tell me how sick you were. -I was afraid.
我知道你把我带到这来  可我没法在医院工作
I knew you'd bring me here. And I can't work in the hospital.
我能做什么
What I can do?
要怎么样我才能帮上忙 丽姬娅
How I can help, Ligeia?
你是指这个
Do you mean it?
我什么都愿意做
I'll do anything.
如果我可以回到我的家 罗马尼亚的马诺尔
If I could go home where I was born: Romanova Manor.
医生一说你可以安全乘坐飞机我们就登上航班
We'll just get on a plane as soon as the doctors say it's safe to fly.
但是很多年前我们家族就失去了那庄园
But my family lost the manor years ago.
我可以买下它 我可以付任何费用
I'll buy it. I'll pay any price.
我爱你
I love you.
在那黑暗和光明中结合的爱情
-By the bonds of love in darkness and light...
别担心这些
Don't worry about it...
我爱你   我不能放弃你
I love you, I can't stand to see you this way.
黑海 乌克兰 东欧
丽姬娅 让我给你介绍
Ligeia, let me introduce you.
我是弗拉索夫  你好（这句我猜的查来查去又不是英语）
I am Vaslov. -Dentombre.
弗拉索夫是看门人  他为我们看管这个地方
Vaslov is the caretaker. He's gonna watch the place for us.
我希望你在这里能感觉像在家一样
I hope this place will feel like home to you too.
这是… 洛尔莱
And this is... Lorelei?
是弗拉索夫斯的侄女  我侄女 是的
-Who is Vaslovs' niece? My niece, yes.
嗨 洛而莱
Hi, Lorelei.
你好
-Dentombre.
她 不太能说话 发生一些坏事
She is, uh, can't speak so much. Some bad things happen.
所以现在他和我在一起
So now she is with me.
我祖父设计的
My grandfather designed it.
为超自然实验
For metaphysical experiments.
那么 你怎么想
So, what do you think?
这非常不寻常
It's rather unusual.
我希望我们能在这个房间里结婚
I wish we could have been married in this room.
孩子们会给这地方带来些生气
The child will bring some life back to this place.
带回生气 真有意思
To bring life back... Interesting.
甜蜜的美梦 莱恩
Sweet dreams, Len.
你和你母亲的名字一样
You and your mother have the same name?
我们很亲密
We were close...
非常亲密
...so close.
我可以看到她的灵魂在无尽的虚空中受尽折磨
I could see her spirit when it was sucked into the great emptiness.
我的灵魂 乔纳森 可以去任何我想去的地方
My spirit, Jonathan, will go where I will it to.
你不应该说这些
You... you shouldn't talk like that.
你应该在床上休息 服药
You should be in bed. Take your medicine.
如果你想要我感觉好些
-If you want me to feel better,
从地窖里拿点酒上来
get me some wine from the cellar.
快些
年份醇一点的
Something old.
如此亲密
So close now.
实验已经接近结束
The experiment is almost finished.
该死的老鼠
我要做到历史上无人能做到之事
-I want to do what no one in history has accomplished.
不是魔法也不是科学  而是把两者结合在一起
Not with magic nor science, but a combination of both.
我提取出了人类灵魂的精华
I have extracted the essence of the human soul...
并且控制了它们
...and contained them.
借用我祖先的黑魔法  我可以迫使它们遵从于我的灵魂
With the black magic of my ancestors, I will bind them to my own soul.
它们可以让我的灵魂足够强大到去任何我想要去的地方
They will make my spirit powerful enough to go where I will it.
从人类时代开启以来
Since the dawn of man,
死亡索取走每一个凡人的灵魂 就像我母亲的结局
death has claimed every mortal soul, like I saw it did my mothers'.
我不会重蹈她的覆辙
I will not share her fate,
但我一定要加快进度
but I must work quickly.
在我身体里的疾病越来越强大
As the disease within me grows stronger,
控制乔纳森让我越来越虚弱
My hold on Jonathan is weakening.
你好 嗨
Hello, hey.
恭喜 我就知道你一定能完成
Congratulations. I always knew you could make it.
你在这做什么
What are you doing here?
我必须见到你
I need to see you.
你是怎么回来这里的
How did you even get back here?
你忘记了我有钱 你父亲还没有死
You forget I have money? Your father never did.
我相信你一路飞过来不是为了羞辱我
-I'm sure you didn't fly all the way here just to insult me?
今晚和我共进晚餐
Have dinner with me tonight.
我看了纽约时报上关于你演出的报道
I read the notice in the Times, about your performance.
我想这可能是最后的机会能跟你谈谈
I figured it would be the last chance I'd get to talk to you.
发生了什么 乔纳森
What happened to you, Jonathan?
我不知道 我很诚实的说不知道
I don't know. I honestly don't.
罗威娜 你看上去
Rowena, you look...
那么漂亮
...beautiful.
你看上去
You look...
与众不同
...different.
在今晚看到你之前我不知道有多么想你
I didn't know how much I missed you, until I saw you tonight.
我
I don't...
我不想伤害你
I don't want to hurt you.
罗
Row...
聆听我 乔纳森
Hear me, Jonathan.
回到我身边
Come back to me.
我不能 罗威娜
I can't, Rowena.
上帝啊 我太愚蠢了
God, I'm so stupid.
早上好 医生
Good morning, doctor.
早上好
Good morning.
事实了，应该是教授
Actually, it's Professer.
请叫我乔纳森
But, please, call me Jonathan.
你不是医生
You're not a doctor?
不是，我是有学位 文学上的
No, I have a Ph.D, but in literature.
我还以为
I just thought that...
以为什么
Thought what?
我还以为你是个医生
I assumed you were a doctor, what with...
在那个地下室里面做实验
...all experiments in the basement.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我让莱恩自由了
-I've set Len free.
但我没法让他的生命回来
But I can't give him his life back.
最终这些都不重要 乔纳森
None of it matters in the end, Jonathan.
这就是最终结局 我承诺给你的
It's the end. I promise you that.
不 乔纳森 我的工作不只是为了我自己
No, Jonathan. My work isn't just for me.
跟我说说
Tell me something,
你为什么要和我结婚
Why did you marry me?
因为我爱你
Because I love you.
狗屁
Bullshit.
你是为了钱才和我结婚
You married me for my money.
如果大学开除了你那么我可以支持你的工作
I could support your work if the university failed you.
-我就知道 -不 乔纳森 你一定要相信我
-I know.  -No, Jonathan, you have to believe me.
我会安排你去医院的 他们会照顾好你
I'll set you up at the hospital. They can take care of you,
我会支付任何费用
I'll pay for everything.
和我在一起 乔纳森
Stay with me, Jonathan.
你对我做了什么 你做了什么 你控制了我的思想
What did you do to me? What did you do? Did you control my mind?
你毁了我的生活 你毁了一切
You took my life away! You took everything!
服从我 乔纳森
Obey me, Jonathan.
你太虚弱了
You're weak.
你再也不能控制我
You don't control me anymore.
- 我要离开你      - 为了她
- I'm leaving you. -For her?
她什么都不是
She's nothing.
再见
Goodbye.
我会
I am and I will be...
由始至终  起始与终结
For the Alpha and Omega, the beginning and end...
屈从与我
Bind yourselves to me!
Bind yourselves to me...
嘿  你真的应该把落叶清理干净
Hey. You really should rake the leaves out here.
是啊
Yeah..
听着
Listen...
那里
There's, uhm...
有人在那看你
...somebody here to see you.
谁
Who?
相信我 我想他有些重要东西是你需要的
Well trust me, I think he has something important that you need to hear.
我认识你吗
Do I know you?
我们需要谈谈
We need to talk.
她死了
She's dead.
我知道
I know.
罗 你想要什么
Row, what do you want?
我只想要帮助你
I just want to help you.
看看她 她是那么可爱
Look at her. She's so sweet.
我真的想为她做些什么
I really want to do something for her.
你还好吗 洛尔莱
Are you alright, Lorelei?
洛尔莱  你觉得你和你叔叔跟我们一起去美国怎么样
Lorelei, how would you feel about you and your uncle coming to America with us?
我能要个深盘披萨吗
Can I have deep-dish pizza?
什么
What?
我现在宣布你们成为夫妻
I now pronounce you man and wife.
你可以亲吻新娘
You may kiss the bride.
恭喜
Congratulations.
洛尔莱
Lorelei...
嘿 罗威娜
Hey, Rowena.
我觉得我们犯了个错误
I think we made a mistake.
什么 父亲
What, Dad?
我觉得我们犯了个巨大的错误
I think we made a big mistake!
关于什么
About what?
关于来到这 在这个房子里 我们犯了一个错误
About being here, in this house. We made a mistake.
就好像她还在这里 在这座该死的城堡里
It's like she's still here, in this Godamned... castle!
这让我毛骨悚然 罗 是吧
And it's creeping me out, Row, alright?
这地方让我抓狂
This place is making me crazy.
听着 我知道你以为我喝多了 是不是
Listen, I know you think I'm a drunk. Don't you?
我没有责备你 但现在不是时候
'Cos I don't blame you. But that aint it right now.
这都不会发生的 好吗
That aint what's happening, ok?
我希望你可以等等
I wish you would just wait.
-为了什么  -为我 我们会尽可能快的
-For what? -For me, we'll go as soon as I can.
这不会太久的 我也不想呆在这
It's not gonna be long, I don't want to be here either.
好吗
Ok?
好
-Ok.
我
I am...
我会在这
...and I will be.
你怎么不睡觉
你有些不对劲
跟我走
回来
到这来 叔叔
是什么这么重要
洛尔莱，你不是真正的你
峡谷里一阵阵的
The bagpipes are calling...
风笛声传来
...from glen to glen...
我没办法呆在这
I can't stand being here.
还有多久 我只是觉得 我就是觉得她还在...
How much longer? I just, I feel like, I almost feel like she's...
若鲜花枯萎之时你来此
If you come when the flowers are dying...
我会得到更多
-I'm getting some more of that!
我猜爸爸又喝酒了
Guess dad's drunk again.
这就是你在一座有酒窖的房子里能找到的东西
That what you get for living in a house with wine cellar.
这都是鬼话
This is all bullshit.
我带走罗威娜 明天 我就离开这
'Cos I'm gonna take Rowena, tomorrow, and I'm gonna leave!
还不行
-Not yet.
对不起 这什么意思 你在说什么
Sorry, what was that? What did you say?
我最好去看看洛尔莱  爸爸也许把她吓个半死
I better go see if Lorelei's ok. Dad's probably scared her half to death.
洛尔莱
Lorelei?
洛尔莱 你在这吗
Lorelei, are you in there?
洛尔莱 你在这干什么
Lorelei, what are you doing in here?
我睡不着
-I can't sleep.
我也是
Me neither.
你想要去喝这些 是不是
You're not going to drink that, are you?
叔叔说这些有助于睡眠
-Uncle says it helps make me sleepy.
他告诉你的 你叔叔说的
He tells you that? Your uncle said that?
好吧
Well...
也许这真的有助于睡眠
...maybe this will help me get sleepy,
但我觉得牛奶和饼干对你更有助
but I think that milk and cookies might work better for you.
告诉你
Tell you what...
我们回楼上吧 我会陪你一起直到你入睡
Let's go back upstairs, and I will lay with you until you fall asleep.
然后明天
And then tomorrow...
乔纳森和我会给一个大惊喜 好吗
Jonathan and I have a huge surprise for you, ok?
给你的惊喜
A surprise for you.
上帝 我真的有点头晕
God, I feel really dizzy.
我们要去哪
Where are we going?
洛尔莱 这条路不对
Lorelei, this is the wrong way.
过来，我指给你
Come, I show you.
罗威娜
-Rowena!
罗 罗
Row, Row.
叫救护车
Call an ambulance.
洛尔莱 你听到我的话吗
Lorelei, you hear me?
洛尔莱 去找弗拉索夫 快去
Lorelei, get Vaslov. Go!
乔纳森
Jonathan...
你还好吗
Are you ok?
我怎么了 你晕过去了
What happened to me? -You fainted.
我正准备带你去医院
I'm going to take you to a hospital.
罗威娜
Rowena...
你父亲
...your dad...
他摔下去
...he fell.
他死了
He's dead.
我不敢相信这里面你一点关系都没有
I can't believe there's nothing wrong with you.
我告诉过你
-I told you!
我们现在可以回家了 – 不
So now we go home? - No.
什么
What?
我不明白
I don't understand.
我只是不想被这个地方击溃
I just don't want to let this place defeat me.
你现在还想呆在这        - 是的
So now you want to stay? -Yes.
好吧 洛尔莱 我猜我们要呆在这
Well, Lorelei, I guess we're staying.
洛尔莱 亲爱的 你觉得可以到外面去玩一会吗
Lorelei, sweetie, do you think you can go play outside for a minute?
我想和乔纳森说几句话
I need to talk to Jonathan.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我们不能照看她
We can't take care of her.
但是是你说你想要她和我们一起回家的啊
-But you just said you wanted to take her home with us.
好吧 我错了 这的确是个高尚的想法 但是 不
Well, I was wrong. It was a noble idea, but, no.
罗威娜 她无亲无故 我们甚至不知道弗拉索夫在哪
-Rowena, she doesn't have anybody. We don't even know where Vaslov is.
好吧 找个其他人来照顾她 乔纳森
-Well, find someone to take care of her, Jonathan!
我很惊奇你想要来这 罗
-I'm surprized you wanted to come here, Row.
这是我的另一面
It's a different side of me.
这真是个美丽的遗产 不是么 乔纳森
It really is a beautiful estate, isn't it, Jonathan?
这只是感觉起来是如此生机勃勃
It just feels so alive.
照您所求 一杯上好的白兰地
-As requested: a fine old brandy.
罗威娜
Rowena...
什么
What?
有什么东西使你恼怒
Something bothering you?
是的
Yes.
就是你想要抛弃洛尔莱的事情
It's the way you dismissed Lorelei like that.
瞧 这并不是个鲁莽的决定 我有认真思考过
Look, it wasn't just a rash decision. I'd thought about it
这只是看起来很
-It just seemed so...
什么
What?
你想要说什么
What are you gonna say?
冷漠
'Cold'?
我看起来对你很冷漠吗
Do I seem cold to you now?
我看起来很冷漠吗
Do I feel cold?
罗威娜
Rowena?
什么
What?
我只想说你的名字
I just wanted to say your name.
帮帮我
Help me.
帮帮我 洛尔莱
Help me, Lorelei.
首先  这么快你就从你父亲的死亡中恢复过来
First, It was how quick you got over your dad dying.
你知道 我估计 当你提出那女孩送走的时候
You know, I figured, when you sent the girl away,
你做事的方式
It was the way you did it.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
你穿衣服的风格
And the way you dress now...
真的 乔纳森 你这么做没有意义
Really, Jonathan, you're not making any sense.
认真的 这就是你的感觉
But really, it was the way you feel...
你死在
You died...
我的环抱中
...in my arms...
丽姬娅
Ligeia.
我是那么想要你了解真正我
I so wanted you to know that it was me.
我再也不能控制我自己
I could not keep it to myself any longer.
回答我
Answer me.
你对罗威娜做了什么
What did you do with Rowena?
她不在了
She's gone!
这么做使你不安了 乔纳森
Did that excite you, Jonathan?
我有些东西要告诉你
I have something to tell you.
这是你吗
Is that you?
是的 我有很多话要跟你说
Yes! I have much to tell you.
你看起来美极了
You look beautiful.
我不能离开
I couldn't stay away.
这是谁的身体并不重要 不是吗 乔纳森
It doesn't matter whose body it is, isn't that right, Jonathan?
你知道 你在我心中一直占有一席之地
You know, you will always have a special place in my heart.
这感觉起来像谁
Who did that feel like?
这当然是丽姬娅
That was definitely Ligeia.
不论我必须去做什么 我不想去死
I am not going to die, no matter what I have to do.
有一天我们都会死
Someday we must die.
不
No.
听着    我们不用付出什么代价
Listen, we will never have to pay that price.
我们可以长生不死
We can live forever.
只要让一些其他傻瓜来代替我们去死
Let some other fools take our place and die.
但是你一定要保证 乔纳森
But you must commit, Jonathan.
哦，我保证
Oh, I am committed.
饮下一个新的生命
Drink to a new life.
乔纳森
Jonathan...
不
No!
去死 乔纳森 去死
Die, Jonathan, die!
罗 醒醒
Row, wake up.
醒醒
Wake up.
乔纳森
Jonathan...
是你吗  罗  是你吗
Is it you, Row? Is it you?
我们成功了
We did it.
我们成功了 我们成功了
Yeah, we did it. Yeah, we did.
看！这是个狂欢的晚上在凄凄凉凉的暮年！
Lo! 'tis a gala night.
Within the lonesome latter years!
The Conqueror Worm(征服者爬虫)"是Edgar Allan Poe(埃德加·艾伦·坡)在1843年的作品。
有群蝉翼仙子，脸上蒙着轻纱，热泪涟涟
An angel throng, bewinged, bedight
In veils, and drowned in tears,
端坐戏院里，观看一出恐惧和希望交织的悲剧
Sit in a theatre, to see
A play of hopes and fears,
乐队时作时辍地奏出 飘飘渺渺的天外仙曲
While the orchestra breathes fitfully，
The music of the spheres.
丑角乔扮凌霄的天帝
Mimes, in the form of God on high,
咕哝不停，声音低低，飞东飞西地往返无常
Mutter and mumble low,
And hither and thither fly-
只是傀儡，横冲直撞，听凭无形巨掌牵上牵下
Mere puppets they, who come and go
At bidding of vast formless things
无形巨掌瞬息换景
That shift the scenery to and fro,
扑扑秃鹰翅膀，飞降,灾祸，看不清
Flapping from out their
Condor wings Invisible Woe!
这出戏真是五光十色！啊，常记心头。千万莫忘！
That motley drama- oh, be sure
It shall not be forgot!
人群不停追逐“幻影”，伸手捕捉，永远失望，
With its Phantom chased for evermore,
by a crowd that seize it not,
绕圈回旋地兜来转去，始终回到同一地方，
Through a circle that ever returneth in
To the self-same spot,
剧中情节多的是恐惧和罪恶，有的是疯狂。
And much of Madness, and more of Sin,
And Horror the soul of the plot.
折腾蠢动！一声哀吟，
It writhes!- it writhes!- with mortal pangs
灯火转暗，一一隐熄
Out- out are the lights- out all!
好似棺套罩上灵枢，
And, over each quivering form,
The curtain, a funeral pall,
帷幕势比骤雨，倏地落下
Comes down with the rush of a storm,
脸色刷白，双目茫茫，
While the angels, all pallid and wan,
Uprising, unveiling, affirm
公认台上悲剧名唤“人生”，
That the play is the tragedy, "Man,"
And its hero...
主角便是“毒蛊霸王
The Conqueror Worm.